My name is Dilip Singh. Let's
discuss some of the trailer [Music] that has been launched. The
money is normal. When we sell a policy to someone, we
sell insurance by just saying that it is
overall. It is
difficult to sell it.
You cannot explain it unless you know all its features and everything.
In today's session, we will
learn about the policy, what are its features, what are the
benefits in it, how will the customer
enroll, after that we will
learn about the plan process and also about the
endorsement process. If
some mistakes have been made in the policy while purchasing it, then
how will we get it corrected, how will we get it corrected,
we will also
learn about that and how to do it. Let me
start the presentation.
Today's policy
is whose policy.
ICICI Lombard is the fourth
largest insurance company in India,
but it is the largest insurance company.
[Music] It
started in 2019 when the
insurance sector was opened for the private sector.
If I said that it
is the largest private sector company, then the
claim processing is the best in India.
More than 99% of the claims are processed
and out of that also 96% are paid out
to the customer in the first 3 months.
Now let us talk about the policy we are talking about.
This
family policy
can be sold to a citizen whose age is between 18 years. The
premium did not change. The premium ranged
from Rs. 3500 to Rs. 5664. The premium would be charged according to the
age.
In the new policy, the
premium would be charged according to the age. In the
old policy, only two options were available,
one could take a policy of Rs. 100000 or Rs. 2 lakh.
In the new policy, the customer
has five options.
Someone wants to know whether
you already have any disease or not.
19 questions are asked about which diseases you have.
If the customer already has any of those
19 diseases, then we cannot sell this policy to him. There are
some additional and some very good ones in the policy.
Benefits have been added
due to which it has become a bit expensive. The
first thing is that unlimited reset
benefit has been given in it,
under which
if the customer has
used some of his insurance, then he can get it
reset again by paying additional premium and can get
his insurance made again.
In this, if the
policy is not used, then next
year at the same premium, he will get a
higher amount of cover.
Apart from the English claims, if someone is getting
treatment from another student, then that can also be
done, that
means the benefit can also be availed from home
and the
premium amount depends on
how many people the
policy is being taken for. So,
in this, the customer has a choice,
if the customer wants, he can take it for himself alone or can also
take it for husband and wife. If there is
husband, wife and one child, then there is a
need for husband, wife and one child
and husband and wife two  It can be done for the child,
maximum two children can be added, they
can be only two, they
should be between 21 years to 7 years, the child who will be added in this, the
age of the child should have
completed 90 days, that is, a child
from 91st day to
20 years can be added in this,
as soon as the child turns 21 years, he will be
out of the policy, that is, he will be added till 20 years, he
can avail the benefit for 20 years and 364 days, there are
different benefits in this, about which I will
tell you separately in the formalities, the first
benefit is in-patient hospital, that is, if
someone is admitted in a hospital, then
after admission, the expenses in the hospital, it is
necessary to be admitted
in the hospital and at least
24 hours hospital,
so whatever expenses will be incurred on treatment under this, be it the
cost of medicine or
operation
[Music] This can be
availed in two ways.
If the customer is admitted to a panel hospital,
if there is a hospital on the insurance company's panel, then the
treatment will be cashless. The
customer will not have to pay from his pocket. The
second way to avail the
benefit is if there is
no admission in the panel hospital, then the
customer gets an admission and
after making the payment,
whatever bill the customer has received, whatever expenses he has incurred,
all the bills are
attached with the information and he files a claim. On
clearing the claim, the
second benefit that the insurance company gives is for care
surgery and DK treatment.
Under the old policy, all types of
surgeries or treatments have to be
admitted in the hospital, but they are
not admitted for 24 hours. The customer is
admitted for a few hours and the treatment is
given to him on the same day. For example,
you know that Moti, if you have an
operation on a person for hydrocele, he
is discharged in 6-8 hours.  It will be done.
Apart from this,
under treatment, there is some life saving
treatment like if the customer gets poisoned or
bitten by a snake
due to which the customer may die,
he is treated and it is
possible that he recovers and is
discharged within 8 hours or 10 hours. So,
all those treatments are covered under this
and there is no limit on the amount for which the
customer has
purchased the policy. The
third benefit in this is the expenses incurred during pre-hospitalization,
which the
insurance company is already paying. But
if
before being admitted to the hospital, a customer has
paid the doctor's fee, has undergone any tests or has any
claim related to the same disease, then the customer can make a claim by submitting the bill etc.
to the insurance company.
Apart from this, after being discharged from the hospital,
if he has any claim or has incurred any expenses in any
test, then
he can also pay that from the insurance company. The
fourth thing under this is room
rent and  The gapping of ICU is
one
percent per day of the policy amount taken and the capping of ICU is
two percent per day of the false seal amount taken,
which is
kept closed, that is, if we talk about room rent, if there
is insurance of ₹1 lakh then ₹1000 per day, if there is
insurance of ₹200000 then ₹2000 per
day is for 3 lakhs, then ₹3000 per day is for 4 lakhs
and 425 days and 5 lakhs will be given as per
daily basis, similarly as per the
insurance,
if there is more expenditure than that, then
in such a situation, the
customer himself will have to bear the expenditure beyond the limit,
[Music] There is
reset benefit
under unlimited reset benefit, like if
someone has taken a policy, let me
tell you an example, if a customer has
taken a policy of ₹5 lakhs and four people
are covered on it, the customer himself, his wife and two
If any of the children who are covered falls
seriously ill, suppose nowadays
if a bill of Rs. 3.30 lakhs comes, then
for the remaining time in the year,
he has
only a limit of Rs. 1.5 lakhs left, that is up
to Rs. 1.5 lakhs.
In this policy, the customer has the option to
see a little premium and after
seeing the additional premium, he
will reset his limit again.
After getting it reset,
if some expenses increase due to illness, then
he can get it done as many times as he wants, there is no
limit on it.
If you have taken car insurance for yourself
and you have not cleared the car insurance, then
when you pay the insurance premium for the next year, then
under the bonus, you have to pay less premium. It
reduces your premium.
What happens in medical insurance, if you have
not taken the benefit of the insurance, if you have
not used it, then next
year when you get the
policy reviewed, you will have to pay the
same premium, but you will have to pay an additional
10% extra.
Similarly, if it is not used for 4 years
So, if you do
not spend 10 years continuously instead of 5 lakhs, then there will be a benefit of Rs 10 lakhs.
As soon as it is used in any year, then the
next year it will be
reset and you will reach 5 lakhs again. The
seventh benefit is in this, in-patient
's English
claim in normal medical insurance or in an English hospital which accepts English
claim, is
covered.
Under this policy, in-patients in
what are called Ayush hospitals, alternative medicine hospitals, for example, if
someone has to get
treatment and their treatment is
not in an allopathy hospital but
in a homeopathy hospital or
in an Ayush hospital or if anyone is getting
treatment in an alternative medicine hospital, then that is also covered.
People are also admitted in Ayurveda hospitals,
treatment is done there too and
operations are done there too, so all those things
are also covered in it and in that, the same amount as if
you get
treatment done under the supervision of a normal hospital, you have to
inform the insurance company in advance
if you have already informed and  The
doctor is treating you, I am
supervising your treatment, so
you can get money for that too by playing games from the insurance company.
Now I will give two examples of this. The
first example is that right now,
like in Corona, in the current situation of Corona,
many people have
medical insurance.
If someone gets treatment done, then it can be availed
under this policy.
[Music]
If you get dialysis done in the hospital, then it can
cost from 10-15000 rupees to 30-35000 rupees.
How many times should you get it done? Each
time the dialysis will cost that much. Okay, so it is
expensive for the insurance company also,
but there is an alternative to it. There are
many medical
companies which rent dialysis machines for ₹1, which are
₹570000 per day. So, if
someone gets the treatment done at home by taking that machine, then
ISRO company
approves that too.
You can get the money for that too. Take care of the
expenses of someone.
[Music] If the kidney has
deteriorated and someone has died, then instead of
finding it, it is being
administered to the patient or if
someone is getting a kidney transplant
or a liver transplant, then the
cost of that is also there
in the old policy [Music] which is Rs. 3540 for the
insurance of 2 lakhs,
which is Rs. 4956 and
even Rs. 566, that type of premium is
not there in this policy. In this policy, as
I said in the beginning, the premium will
depend on the
age of the buyer, whether it is between 21 to 25,
between 26, between 36 to 45, between
46 to 50, between 51 to 55
or between 56 to 60, for
how many people is it being taken, has
he taken it for himself alone,
for husband and wife, there are no children, only one
child,
if the
age of the buyer is between 2100 to 25
and he is married alone  If he is not single
then the premium he will have to pay will be
Rs 2127, similarly if the husband is
buying it for his wife then it will be Rs 3166
and if
the husband is buying it for his wife and one child then it will be
Rs 42 and Rs 18 and if
the husband is buying it for his wife and two children then similarly, as per the
different amounts he will
buy and the age of the
buyer, the
minimum amount he will have to pay will be Rs 2127 and the maximum amount will be Rs
26000 i.e. if he is above 55 and the buyer's age is between 55 to 60 years and he is buying it for the entire family but if his age is between 55 to 60 then it will be around Rs 26000 i.e. Rs 25992 but if the buyer is
only 25 years old and he has two children,
husband and wife, the
best claim giving company in India is getting the
insurance number ICC
[Music] from
this also  96% of the time, the delay that occurs
within the first 3 months, whether the
delivery is of 3 months
or more, is
due to the customer.
[Sangeet]
Okay, if we look at the premium of the rest of the companies, then this much is charged, as per that, it is
very competitive, there is
no need to get any medical done even after 45,
if you take a policy from outside and the
buyer is above 45 then
he has to get a medical done, there is
no need to get a medical done here, any
physical document
[Sangeet] It
is necessary to have a printer so that you
can print the insurance document and give it to them, and it is necessary to have a fingerprint
scanner
so that you can sell it to them and verification can be done, the
customer cannot get admitted in the hospital, he
cannot avail the benefit of this policy,
but when he runs it for one year, it
starts from the first day of the next year, if you take it for the first
time, then for the first 3 days only
accident benefit will be given
before taking it, if there is any Priya Interesting
Disease already  If you have any disease, its
treatment is not covered under this policy. If you
run the policy for 24 months continuously i.e. 2 years, then from the third year onwards, everything is
covered. There are
some diseases and some treatments which are
not covered at all by this policy,
related to childbirth, i.e. if you are getting any
replacement done, then you are getting eye
surgery done, you
wear glasses, you are getting an
operation done to remove them, then
that is not covered. If you are getting
plastic surgery done under this, then that is not covered. If you are getting
treatment done for not being able to give birth, then that is not covered. If you are paying any
kind of administration charge, you are getting any kind of experiment
[musical]
instrument installed on you which replaces the functioning of your
internal organ inside or outside your body,
as it has been done as an example, you are getting a
holster mounted,
which is a machine because it is said to
replace the function of your heart
and it is hung near the chest of people, which
is covered. There are some special conditions
under which if you undergo sinus surgery  If so, the maximum amount
that the insurance company will pay for sinus surgery is Rs.
35,000. If there is a
helmet, that is, if there is any mental
illness, then for that they say up to Rs. 30,000 for that, if the
operation is being done, whether to get fibernet treatment
or not, it is a robotic operation, through a machine, through a
computer report
[Music] so that
when that child grows up and becomes an adult, if
he has some disease, a serious disease, cancer
etc. or if blood oxygen can be
produced, then if he has to undergo any treatment
or some implant is
being replaced,
in such treatment,
he will get only half the amount of the policy amount, that is, if this is a plus
insurance, then 50 thousand and 5 lakh, 2.5
lakh should be
paid within 30 days. If there is a
delay of more than 30 days, then the customer is charged a penalty
[Music]
Apart from this, you must have seen in insurance that
insurance companies are cutting money
[Music] I will
tell you that the first thing is that
90% of the bill is borne by the insurance company
Bharti and 10% is borne by the customer.
This happens and the second thing is whenever
someone is admitted in the hospital then it is
very important to inform the insurance company by calling in advance.
If the client is
your treatment is going on and you have to be
admitted in the hospital then in such a
situation the
customer should
inform the insurance company 48 hours i.e. 2 days in advance and if there
is no green line or if there is an emergency then
within 24 hours of admission we will inform the customer
that your treatment is going on here
[Sangeet] it is
helpful for you and there is
no problem in getting another one then as soon as the
claim form
is submitted to the insurance company then the money is also credited
to the account within two weeks,
okay otherwise it
takes time, a better way is to inform the
insurance company in advance
how the policy will be booked and when a
customer comes then when the customer comes
how will the customer search be done customer ID
mobile number or account number
[Sangeet]
first will be
choose the hospital and after that click on the enroll button a
pop up message  A prompt will come in which consent will be sought from the consult customer, we will
click on it and ok,
after proving that the customer is registered, the phone will open,
in opening the form, first of all,
for a single individual, the
husband and wife are taking
insurance of ₹3 lakh, ₹4 lakh, ₹5 lakh, we will check their age between
26 and 30,
35 to 45, 51 to
or not, if yes is written in any of them
[music], the
policy is not valid for the customer, there should be
no in all of them, one thing will be tried that
whatever is being
told is correct, so after
filling everything correctly and saying yes in all, we will
click on it,
after that the form will open, first of all, the
details of the individual in whose name the policy is being booked, their bank
details etc. will be filled, after filling all these, the
application
option depends  At the beginning,
while buying the policy, whatever you have selected on the first page, whether you want to take it
alone, for two people, for
three people,
accordingly the details will be given and you will have to
accept the declaration.
As soon as you accept and click next, the
customer care register, the
certificate can be taken out later also
[Sangeet],
it gets generated, then the certificate
number is also written on the meter, at
this time, the same number is required while taking the claim,
which
is through SMS, after 30 days the customer gets a
message
[Sangeet],
from there you can get the number, otherwise
if you want to take a printout on paper, then you
can visit the ICCL number website, there you will go to
health care, go to the
customer section, go to the customer section and
choose the I card,
there in the type of policy,
corporate is entered,
after entering, you will enter and click on search, then the
certificates, that is, the certificates of
all the people, you want to take out one by one,
if you want to cancel the policy, then there is a
free loan period of 15 days in the first 15 days  If the
customer returns the policy, he will get a
full refund without any loss of money. He
can do it from there also.
If he wants to do it through you, then the request will go through you. You can do it through all
three of you by
sending an email to thefinobank.com and by
entering the policy details and customer details, you
can make the request.
Whatever documents, whatever details you will enter in the
request, will be
shared with the insurance office team and
[sangeet] once it is
shared there, the
money will be credited to the customer's account within three days of the day your request is processed. But
if
you are not able to do it on the first day, if
you have placed the request anytime between the second, third day and 12:00 pm, then the
money will be credited back to the customer's account within 10 days.
[sangeet] If you want to
change the name of the father or husband, then an
ID proof will be required.
To change the name of the husband, you will have to
submit such an ID proof on which the name of the father or husband will be mentioned. The
mobile number can be
changed.
[Music]
What our staff does is they generate a ticket,
they
generate it for the tickets and there
all the requests are given in the format which is
made in Excel, in
that approval of the zonal is also required
which is possible only for that, so after
taking the approval of the zonal and when it is uploaded then the helpdes
masti kar insurance operation will
forward it to ICC Lombard
within 5 days,
your request for endorsement has been sent to
us and within 20 days the
new document is prepared and
uploaded, then the new certificate
with any changes that need to be made can be
uploaded
[Music]
Directly
go to the ICICI Lombard office and
fill the form there and all the documents, the
claim will come through you, so the claim form will be sent,
after filling the form
you will collect all the documents, after that
your local Fino
official is there
You will give it to them, after giving it to them, they will
scan it and create a ticket and the
insurance operation species of Sapphire will
check it in the soft copy and will see that all the
details are correct, then they will say to
send the document, today the document
goes to our Mumbai head office in Mumbai
and after going to the head office, when the process is done and the
money is transferred to the customer's account, I make it a
little bigger, the
claim form should be filled in original, the
discharge summary of which has to be submitted in original, when you are discharged from the hospital, then
all the hospital bills have to be submitted in original,
whatever payment you have made, the
receipt of that is there  You have to submit it in original. You have
shown it to the doctor and
for consultation, if you have shown something big to the doctor, then
you will have to give its photocopy. Be it
CT scan or sonography,
its photocopy has to be attached.
If any investigation has been done, then the
medicine expenses, as per the description, then
its bills have to be attached in original.
If you have paid the hospital expenses separately on loan, then if the
hospital is taking reversal, if the
treatment is done, then submit it to the hospital. So,
whatever bills you have, pharmacy
medicines, if there is a
case of accident, then you will have to
attach its photocopy. And for the test, if any
such charge has been made by the
doctor from the test officer,
you will have to attach its original bill
like Aadhar card, PAN card
cancellation
[music] has to be done
and at the
end,
during the treatment of the disease, how much has been spent for different things, how much has been spent
in the room, how much has been spent
for medicine, how much has it been spent on
theatre, how much has it been spent on operation,
how much has it been spent on medicine,
all these have to be paid separately.  We will
do it as soon as the vertical gets it,
within 21 days the
customer will get the money in his account
[Music]
You will give it to your sales officer, he will
first generate the ticket, it will be cleared from the head office,
after getting the clearance
they will say send the documents here, the
documents will be sent from here to Mumbai but it will take
three-four days to reach there,
then after processing from there they will
give it later, then they will process it, so it takes
35-40 days in total, it is better to go
directly to
such and such a vertical office in Dharam district,
any customer name can be obtained directly from there
[Music]
So it is cashless there, that was all
about this policy for now, if you have
any questions related to it then you
can ask, there is an open forum, if you have
any questions then you can ask, I am
talking to you, I am a distributor,
sir, you had told that there are 19 diseases for
which they cannot give this policy to them,
what are those diseases?  Yes sir,
normally, the
upper diseases that you have are fine
[music], for
some reason,
in the last 6 months, you are asked all these questions, whether you smoke
or not, all these
things are asked, whether you smoke
or not, all these questions are asked,
so what will the customer answer to this,
if the customer is getting treatment,
then he would know, if he is
not getting treatment and after taking the policy, his problem becomes
serious, he gets
some kind of symptoms
and after that he gets treatment, then it will be
covered, it is
not that it will not be covered, he should not
know it beforehand, if he is getting treatment then
he will not get it,
okay sir, its commission chart and when will he
get the commission, there is a machine
[music],
so there is different commission for everyone, the percentage
changes differently, the
commission is given monthly, the insurance
commission will be given for everything else
which you do normally, you do the parameters, you make the
bill payment, it is instant,
okay sir, thank you  Hello You